Cheney Brothers Silk Manufacturing Company Records 1984.0026
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series V: General Accounts, 1847-1927
  - Subseries B: Cash Books, 1848-1927
    - A, 1848 January - 1850 June (Box 86)
    - Cash book, 1850 July - 1853 September (Box 87)
    - Cash book, 1853 November - 1862 Janaury (Box 88)
    - A, 1854 August - 1860 May (Box 89)
    - B, 1860 June - 1864 January (Box 90)
    - C, 1864 January - 1867 January (Box 91)
    - D, 1867 February - 1869 April (Box 92)
    - E, 1869 May - 1871 October (Box 93)
    - F, 1871 November - 1874 January (Box 94)
    - G, 1874 July - 1877 August (Box 95)
    - H, 1877 September - 1879 November (Box 96)
    - I, 1879 December - 1882 March (Box 97)
    - J, 1882 April - 1884 July (Box 98)
    - K, 1884 August - 1886 December (Box 99)
    - L, 1886 December - 1892 January (Box 100)
    - M, 1888 December - 1890 December (Box 101)
    - N, 1890 March - 1891 December (Box 102)
    - O, 1891 November - 1893 June (Box 103)
    - P, 1893 July - 1895 March (Box 104)
    - Q, 1895 April - 1896 September (Box 105)
    - R, 1896 October - 1898 February (Box 106)
    - S, 1898 February - 1900 May (Box 107)
    - K, 1892 June - 1895 December (Box 108)
    - M, 1898 December - 1901 December (Box 109)
    - 1, 1898 June - 1899 September (Box 110)
    - 2, 1899 October - 1901 January (Box 111)
    - 3, 1900 January - 1901 July (Box 112)
    - 4, 1901 January - 1902 August (Box 113)
    - 5, 1901 August - 1903 March (Box 114)
    - 6, 1901 September -1903 March (Box 115)
    - 7, 1903 Janaury - 1904 February (Box 116)
    - 8, 1903 February - 1904 March (Box 117)
    - 9, 1903 July - 1906 March (Box 118)
    - 10, 1906 May - 1909 November (Box 119)
    - 11, 1909 December - 1913 January (Box 120)
    - 12, 1913 February - 1915 December (Box 121)
    - 13, 1916 January - 1916 December (Box 122)
    - 14, 1917 January - 1918 October (Box 123)
    - 15, 1918 November - 1920 May (Box 124)
    - 16, 1920 June - 1922 July (Box 125)
    - 17, 1922 August - 1925 February (Box 126)
    - 18, 1925 March - 1927 (Box 127)
    - Shipping invoices—China raw silk, 1858 August - 1861 April (Box 128)
    - Ledger, 1847-1854 (Box 129)
- Series VI: Blueprints, undated, 1891-1984
  - 41-A Wrought iron machine shop, 1895 (Map-case OS, Folder 1)
  - 41-B Cast iron columns, plates machine shop, 1895
  - 41-C Window frames machine shop, 1895
  - 41-D Plans and elevations machine shop, 1895
  - 41-E North River flagging machine shop, 1903 (Map-case OS:, Folder 2)
  - 41-F South door, central building machine shop, 1903
  - 41-G Shed door, electrical department machine shop, 1903
  - 41-H North door, central building machine shop, 1903
  - 41-I Elevator, 1903
  - 41-J Granite steps, machine shop yard, 1904
  - 41-K Washstand arrangement machine shop, 1984
  - 41-L Elevator guards, 1904
  - 41-N Column plates machine shop, 1903 (Map-case OS:, Folder 3)
  - 41-O Water closets machine shop, 1903
  - 41-P Plans and elevations, proposed machine shop, 1903
  - 41-R Wrought iron beams machine shop, 1903
  - 41-U Window frames and sash machine shop, 1903
  - 41-V Sprinkler system machine shop, 1903
  - 41-W Stone floors for water closets machine shop, 1903
  - 41-Y Wrought iron work machine shop, 1903
  - 41-Z Urinals and partitions machine shop, 1903
  - 41-Z-1 Small parts for porcupine machine in spinning mills, 1919 (Map-case OS:, Folder 4)
  - 41-Z-2 Small parts for porcupine machine, 1919
  - 41-Z-3 Small parts for porcupine drilling machine, 1919
  - 41-Z-4 Small parts for porcupine drilling machine, 1919
  - 41-Z-5 Small parts for porcupine machine, 1919
  - 41-Z-6 Small parts for porcupine machine, 1919
  - 41-Z-7 Small parts for porcupine machine, 1919
  - 41-Z-8 Small parts for porcupine drilling machine, 1919 (Map-case OS:, Folder 5)
  - 41-Z-9 Small parts for porcupine drilling machine, 1919
  - 41-Z-10 Small parts for shop truck machine shop, 1917
  - 41-Z-11 B.I.S. truck machine shop, 1919
  - 41-Z-14 New building location, 1903
  - 41-Z-14 Proposed addition to machine shop, 1902
  - 42-A Underpinning machine shop, 1903
  - 42-B Maple drawer cabinets, tool room, 1917
  - 42-D Welding generator house machine shop, 1912
  - 42-F Cast iron strut machine shop, 1912
  - 42-F-1 Detail of tub rods, reinforcing floor, 1912
  - 42-F-3 Elevator and stairway machine shop, 1912
  - 42-G Lodge and shipping lathe bearing machine shop, undated (Map-case OS:, Folder 6)
  - 42-G-1 Roll squaring chuck machine shop, undated
  - 42-H-1 Dust collecting systems machine shop (2 each), 1913
  - 42-H-2 to 6 Detail of hood grinding machinery machine shop (5 each), 1913
  - 42-I Floor plan machine shop, 1914
  - 42-K-2 Window details machine shop, 1919
  - 42-K-3 Cast iron, wrought iron details machine shop, 1920
  - 42-K-4 Sprinkler layout machine shop, 1919
  - 42-L-1 Plans and elevators machine shop, 1919 (Map-case OS:, Folder 7)
  - 42-L-2 to 3 Framing details machine shop (2 each), 1919
  - 42-L-4 to 5 Skylight details machine shop (2 each), 1919
  - 42-L-6 Plumbing plan machine shop, 1919
  - 42-L-7 Sprinkler layout machine shop, 1919
  - 42-M Addition for toilets machine shop, 1903
  - 43-L Wrought iron work machine shop, 1903 (Map-case OS:, Folder 8)
  - 43-W-1 Lamp crushing box, electrical department, 1926
  - 50-A-1 Detail of head, spinning frame model 1913 (Map-case OS:, Folder 9)
  - 50-A-2 Drilling of roller beam, spinning frame 1913
  - 50-A-3 Roll details, spinning frame model 1913 (4 each), 1913-1914
  - 50-A-4 Detail of gears, spinning frame model 1913
  - 50-A-5 Elevation of gearing end, spinning frame model 1913
  - 50-A-6 Detail of top roll, spinning frame model 1913 (2 each)
  - 50-A-11 Elevation of stands, spinning frame model 1913
  - 50-A-12 Lever for draft gears, spinning frame model 1913, 1914
  - 50-A-14 Gear guards, spinning frame model 1913, 1914
  - 50-A-15 Rollers, yoke and worm gearing details, 1914
  - 50-A-16 Stand details, spinning frame model 1913, 1914
  - 50-A-17 Caps, roller bars, weight details, 1914
  - 50-A-18 Roller bar support, rolls and traves details, spinning frame model 1913, 1914
  - 50-B-1 Roller chain details, Freson Pulling Machine (FPM), 1906 (Map-case OS:, Folder 10)
  - 50-B-2 Details of Freson Pulling Machine (FPM) model 1906
  - 50-B-3 Clutch bearing, circular brush FPM, 1906
  - 50-B-4 Brush attachments FPM, 1906
  - 50-B-5 Roller chain guide FPM, 1906
  - 50-B-6 Wood frame FPM, 1906
  - 50-B-7 Longitudinal section FPM, 1906
  - 50-B-8 Side elevation FPM, 1906
  - 50-C-1 Wood frame FPM model 1907
  - 50-C-2 Roller chain guide FPM 1907
  - 50-D Cast iron frame details FPM 1908
  - 50-E Spinning department, draft and twist tables for spinning frames, undated
  - 50-F-2 Spinning frames (SF) model 1905, 1904
  - 50-F-3 SF model 1905, front roll details, 1911
  - 50-G-1 SF model 1905, front elevation, 1911
  - 50-G-2 SF model 1905, spinning frame head, 1911
  - 50-G-3 SF model 1905, drilling of roller beam for stands and weight lever hooks, 1911
  - 50-G-4 SF model 1905, rolls details, undated
  - 50-G-5 SF model 1905, rolls details, undated (Map-case OS:, Folder 11)
  - 50-G-6 SF model 105, rolls and gears details, 1911
  - 50-G-7 SF model 1905, thread guide board, 1911
  - 50-G-8 SF model 1905, gears, 1911
  - 50-H SF model 1905, roller gearing elevation, head end, 1911
  - 50-I SF model 1905, stands, intermediate, 1911
  - 50-J SF model 1905, details
  - 50-J-1 SF model 1905, details, 1911
  - 50-J-2 SF, 1904
  - 50-J-3 SF model 1905, gearing end elevation
  - 50-J-4 SF model 1905, back roll, 1911 (Map-case OS:, Folder 16)
  - 50-K SF model 1905, roller gearing elevation, foot end, 1911
  - 50-K-1 SF model 1905, end stands, 1911
  - 50-K-2 Silk SF, foot end bottom rolls, 1915
  - 50-K-3 Silk SF, head end bottom rolls, 1915
  - 50-K-4 SF rolls, wood, 1901
  - 50-K-5 SF roller stand, 1900
  - 50-K-6 SF stands, 1900
  - 53-A Carbonizing oven, cross section, 1906 (Map-case OS:, Folder 12)
  - 53-B Carbonizing oven trap, 1906
  - 53-B-1 Iron details for trolley rail, carbonizing equipment, washhouse, 1927
  - 53-B-3 Carbonizing tubs, washhouse, 1927
  - 53-B-4 "I" beam trolley details, washhouse, 1927
  - 53-B-5 Grating, drain to boiling bark, washhouse, 1928
  - 53-C Proposed boiling vats plan and elevation, 1906
  - 53-D Special draper spindle, 1907
  - 53-G Machinery picking room proposed arrangement, 1907
  - 53-H - I Spun silk reel model 1907 (2 each)
  - 53-S - K Spun silk reel model 1907 (2 each)
  - 53-L Proposed rearrangement of machinery picker room, spinning mills, 1907
  - 53-M Cast iron plate details, engine blower, dayroom, spinning mills, 1907
  - 53-N Zigzag basket coils, 1907
  - 53-Q Hanger and guide pulley details, spinning frame drive, 1907 (Map-case OS:, Folder 13)
  - 53-R Hanger and guide pulley details, spinning frame drive, 1907
  - 53-S Hanger and guide pulleys, spinning frame, 1907
  - 53-S-2 Shaft bearing details, hanger and guide pulleys, 1915
  - 53-T - V Hanger and pulleys, spinning frame (3 each), 1907
  - 53-W Planning of shafting, spinning mill #1, 1907
  - 53-Z-8 Skein press, 1917 (Map-case OS:, Folder 14)
  - 53-Z-9 to 11 Aluminum reels (3 each), 1918
  - 53-Z-12 Steamer truck, 1919
  - 53-Z-13 Ribboneze machine, 1917
  - 53-Z-14 Bobbin spindle brake, 1921 (Map-case OS:, Folder 15)
  - 53-Z-15 Con stop counter machine, 1917
  - 53-Z-16 to 17 Saco Lowell machine (2 each), 1918
  - 53-Z-18 Schulmberger machine, 1918
  - 53-Z-19 Old H8.B. spinner, 1916
  - 53-Z-20 Old H8.B. spinner, 1916 (Map-case OS OS:, Folder 1)
  - 53-Z-21 Whiting spinner, 1918
  - 53-Z-22 H & B spinner, 1917
  - 53-Z-23 to 24 Frotteur frame (2 each), 1916
  - 53-Z-25 Schulmberger and S. Lowell finisher, 1919
  - 53-Z-26 Drawing frame, 1916
  - 53-Z-27 Porcupine needle press, 1916
  - 55-T Assembly drawing, reinforcing shaft main drive, 1909 (Map-case OS:, Folder 15)
  - 55-U Column clamp, 1909
  - 55-V Detail of Chock, Main Drive Spinning Mills, 1909
  - 55-W Special cast iron, archer, 1909
  - 55-X Wrought iron details, 1909
  - 55-Y to Z Felt paper embossing roll, 1909; (2 each)
  - 55-Z-5 Transmission materials, 1926; (#1 spinning room)
  - 56-V Columns for dressing building, 1899
  - 57-B-16 Tables for gassing machinery, 1912
  - 57-B-17 Cleaner detail, gassing machinery, 1912
  - 57-B-18 Woodwork detail, controllers, gassing machinery, 1912
  - 57-B-19 Window woodwork detail, gassing machinery, 1912
  - 57-B-20 Burner and frame woodwork detail, gassing machinery, 1913
  - 57-B-21 Detail of cleaner and frame, gassing machinery, 1913
  - 57-B-22(1) Burner and frame detail, gassing machinery, 1913 (Map-case OS:, Folder 16)
  - 57-B-22(2) Woodwork for cleaner frame, gassing machinery, 1913
  - 57-B-23 Cross section, top of cleaner, 1913
  - 57-C Woodwork detail washhouse, 1912
  - 57-D-1 Frame extension, grass ribbon machine, 1912
  - 57-D-2 Rolls and bearings, grass ribbon machine, 1912
  - 57-E-1 Crimper rolls, grass ribbon machine, 1912 (Map-case OS OS:, Folder 2)
  - 57-E-2 Frame and bearings detail, crimper, grass ribbon machinery, 1912
  - 57-F Ball bearing, turntable for I-beam, 1923 (Map-case 20)
  - 57-H-1 Detail of still for trolley, washhouse, 1937
  - 57-J Sketch of wire covers for extractors, washhouse, 1937 (Map-case OS:, Folder 33)
  - 57-K New barks for washhouse, 1937
  - 57-L Steel required for new barks, washhouse, 1937
  - 57-N-2 Section and hanger for overhead work, four new barks at washhouse, 1937
  - 57-M Piping and pit work, new boil of barks, 1937 (Map-case OS:, Folder 17)
  - 57-O Cast iron guide, roving frames, 1912
  - 57-P Brush drive detail, roving frames, 1912
  - 57-P-1 to 2 Brush attachment frame, roving frames, 1914
  - 57-P-3 Cleaner weights for roving frames, 1914
  - 57-P-4 Detail of Brush Drive, 1914
  - 57-P-5 Drive detail, Frotteur frame, 1915
  - 57-Q Cast steel header detail, wash boiler, washhouse, 1912
  - 57-Q-2 Coils detail, wash boiler, washhouse, 1913
  - 57-Q-3 Cast iron supports, coils, wash boiler, washhouse, 1914
  - 57-T Beams and angles, wash boiler, washhouse, 1913
  - 57-V Bevel gears, spinning frames, 1913
  - 57-W Yokes detail, lifting baskets, washhouse, 1913
  - 57-X Cross section, first floor spinning mills, 1913
  - 57-Y-2 Superstructure detail, two new boiling tubs, washhouse, 1913
  - 57-Z Castings detail, remodeled spinning frame, 1913
  - 58-A Detail of flyer button, 1913 (Map-case OS:, Folder 16)
  - 58-B-11 Proposed sole plate, 1913
  - 58-E Traverse motion, yarn gassing machinery, 1914
  - 58-F Cleaner frames cover, 1914
  - 58-G-1 Bracket, worm gear and worm, Rocco counter, roving frame, 1914
  - 58-G-3 Bracket, worm gear and worm, Rocco counter, drawing frames, 1915
  - 58-G-4 Rocco counter application, 1915
  - 58-G-5 Rocco counter application, 1916
  - 58-G-6 Veeder counter application, 1916
  - 58-H Yards separator, spinning frame, 1914 (Map-case OS:, Folder 19)
  - 58-J Singeing and cleaning machine, 1914
  - 58-L-1 to 2 Alterations for drawing frames, 1914; (2 each)
  - 58-M-1 Brush cleaning machine, 1914
  - 58-N Plan of exhaust piping, gassing machine, 1915
  - 58-Z-1 Canopy and silk chute, wool house, undated (Map-case OS:, Folder 16)
  - 58-Z-3 Various small machine parts (pins, screws, washers, rivets, etc.), undated
  - 58-Z-4 - 5 Various small machine parts, 1917; no content
  - 58-Z-6 - 58-Z-8 The American Tool & Machine Co., hydro-extractor, undated; no content
  - 58-Z-11 Rearrangement of trolley track, washhouse, 1906
  - 58-Z-12 - 13 Extension of trolley track, washhouse, 1903; no content
  - 58-Z-14 Cleaning frame spindle, 1891
  - 58-Z-15 Crimping machine, washhouse, 1891
  - 59-C Details, distributing switchboard building window, 1903 (Map-case OS:, Folder 18)
  - 59-E Granite step and door sill, 1903
  - 59-F Sandstone window sill, 1903
  - 59-G Steel roof, addition to switchboard building, 1919
  - 59-H Addition to switchboard building, 1911
  - 59-I Addition to switchboard building, 1919
  - 59-J Granite and brownstone additions, switchboard building, 1911
  - 59-K Ground plan for Forest Street substation, 1903-1919
  - 59-O Plan and elevation, addition, switchboard building, 1906
  - 121-L A.M. Tool & Machine Co., 36′ hydro-extractor with friction pulleys countershaft, 1900 (Map-case OS:, Folder 19)
  - 121-Z 42′ Hydro-extractor, 1900
  - 201-W Date stone, 1901 (Map-case OS OS:, Folder 5)
  - 201-Z -3 Additional mill sites, 1907
  - Misc.(M)-1 Proposed change pioneer lobby, 1952 (Map-case OS:, Folder 17)
  - M-2 Proposed power and steam program, 1937; (3 each)
  - M-3 Underground services map, 1956
  - M-4 Sectional side elevation, 1942
  - M-5 Addition to switchboard building, 1919
  - M-6 Spinning mill diagram plans, 1953; (2 each)
  - M-8 Waste silk storehouse, employees' salesroom and car shed, 1929-1931
  - M-9 Dyestuff and machinery storehouses, 1930-1935
  - M-10 Freight storehouse, 1929-1934